Indiana University Alpha Kappa Psi records, 1925-1983 C510
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Alpha Kappa Psi records
1925-1983
1945-1983
Indiana University Archives
Alpha Kappa Psi. Beta Gamma Chapter (Indiana University)
C510
1.2 cubic feet 3 boxes
The records in this collection document the Indiana University Beta Gamma Chapter of the Alpha Kappa Psi fraternity between the years 1939-1983 with the bulk of the collection being created after 1945. The collection consists of minutes, membership lists, later editions of their constitution and by-laws, chapter songs, president's files, and a limited amount of correspondence within the local chapter and with the national organization.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Biographical Note/Administrative History
The Alpha Kappa Psi Fraternity was founded on October 5, 1904 at New York University and is recognized as the world's oldest and largest professional business fraternity. The objectives of the national fraternity are to further the individual welfare of its members; to foster scientific research in the fields of commerce, accounts and finance, and to promote and advance within higher education courses leading to degrees in business administration. The Beta Gamma Chapter at Indiana University, Bloomington was founded on April 5, 1927, though the earliest records represented in this collection date back only to 1939. The chapter is still operating as of 2013.
Arrangement
Organized in a single series of Administrative files arranged alphabetically.
Scope and Content Note
The collection is organized in a single series of Administrative files which prominently features the minutes of the organization spanning the period from 1945 to 1983. In addition to the minutes there are also the Constitution and By-Laws, president's files, award forms, a limited number of manuals, membership books, and a small collection of songs. Lastly, the collection contains some correspondence of the organization along with correspondence from other chapters of Alpha Kappa Psi.
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory
Archived web sites for this organization may be included in Archive-It: http://www.archive-it.org/collections/219
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database
Acquisition Information
2013/013
Provenance
Transferred from the Kelley School of Business, February 2013.
Appraisal
There were a large number of unclaimed membership certificates that were included in the collection. These were sampled and just one certificate from each year represented was retained. A small amount of blank forms with no evidentiary value were also removed from the collection.
Greek letter societies --Indiana --Bloomington --History --Sources.; Business students --Indiana --Bloomington --History --Sources.; Alpha Kappa Psi. Beta Gamma Chapter (Indiana University) -- Archives; Alpha Kappa Psi. Beta Gamma Chapter (Indiana University) -- Records and correspondence
- Administrative Files, 1925-1983; undated
  - Alpha Kappa Psi Fraternity Membership record books, 1939-1970 (Box 1)
    General
    Note: missing 1958-1962
  - Alpha Kappa Psi Fraternity Membership record books, 1970-1980 (Box 2)
  - Alpha Kappa Psi Autumn Report Forms, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
  - Alpha Kappa Psi Efficiency Rating for College Chapters, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Alpha Kappa Psi Manuals, undated (Box 2)
  - Alpha Kappa Psi Songs, 1925-1967 (Box 2)
  - Applications Forms for Alpha Kappa Psi Awards, circa 1965 (Box 2)
  - Congratulatory Letters, 1956-1961 (Box 2)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1965-1981 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence from other Chapters, 1973-1981 (Box 2)
  - Letter of Appreciation, Hoosier Hills Food Bank, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Membership Certificates, 1964-1983 (Box 3)
  - Membership Lists and Attendance Records, circa 1966-1981 (Box 3)
  - Minutes (Box 3)
    - 1945-1959 (Box 3)
    - 1960-1975 (Box 3)
    - 1976-1979 (Box 3)
    - 1980-1983 (Box 3)
  - President's File (Box 3)
    - 1977 (Box 3)
    - 1978 (Box 3)
  - Proceedings of the 1982 Midwest Regional Conference (Box 3)
  - Trainer, Dale, 1979 (Box 3)